Register of the Kurt Richard Grossmann Papers, 1913-1973
Hoover Institution Archives
- SPEECHES AND WRITINGS, c.1933-1972 (Box 16-36)
  - "Man spricht schon wieder von Hinrichtungen," (People are already talking again about executions), Volk und Zeit, Printed copy., January 1, 1933. (Folder 28: 67)
  - "Mariechen," Aufbau, Printed copy., January 28, 1966. (Folder 28: 68)
  - "Martin Hirsch: Vorkaempfer fuer gerechte und schnelle Wiedergutmachung," (M.H.: early advocate of just and speedy restitution), Aufbau, Printed copy., March 25, 1966. (Folder 28: 69)
  - "Martin Hirsch wird Bundesverfassungsrichter," (M.H. becomes federal constitutional judge), Jedioth Chadashoth, Printed copy., January 10, 1972. (Folder 28: 70)
  - "Martin Luther King, zum zweiten Mal ermordet," (M.L.K. murdered a second time), Jedioth Chadashoth, Printed copy., August 30, 1970. (Folder 29: 1)
  - "Material concerning the Problem of Enemy Aliens," Typescript (carbon copy)., 1942. (Folder 29: 2)
  - "Die Mauer," (The Berlin wall), Telegraf, Mimeographed and printed copies., October 8, 1961. (Folder 29: 3)
  - "Die Mauer und die Menschenrechte," (The Berlin wall and human rights), Sueddeutsche Zeitung, Photocopy., March 21, 1962. (Folder 29: 4)
  - "McClosky, Opponent Nixons," Tagwacht, Printed copy., June 14, 1971. (Folder 29: 5)
  - "The Meaning of the German Elections," Jewish Frontier, Printed copy., December 1953. (Folder 29: 6)
  - "Meier Teich 80jaehrig," Aufbau, Printed copy., January 16, 1970. (Folder 29: 7)
  - "Meinungswandel in den USA," (Change of opinion in the US), Vorwaerts, Printed copy., January 29, 1970. (Folder 29: 8)
  - "Memorandum in der Angelegenheit der Entfuehrung Berthold Jakob/Salomon," (Memo in the matter of the abduction of B.J.S.), Typescript (photocopy). (Folder 29: 9)
  - "Memorandum on the Immigration Problem," Typescript (carbon copy)., July 8, 1947. (Folder 29: 10)
  - "Ein Mensch allein, zum 25. Todestag von Carl von Ossietzky," (A man alone, on the 25th anniversary of the death of C. von O.), Mimeographed and typescript copies., May 3, 1963. (Folder 29: 11)
  - "Menschenrechte: Ideale und Wirklichkeit," (Human rights: ideals and reality), Typescript (carbon copy). (Folder 29: 12)
  - "Menschenrechte - Menschenrechte Covenants," (Human rights - human rights covenants), Typescript (carbon copy)., n.d. (Folder 29: 13)
  - "Menschenrechte und Politik," (Human rights and politics), Typescript (carbon copy). (Folder 29: 14)
  - "Menschlichkeit im Dritten Reich," (Human kindness in the Third Reich), Typescript (carbon copy)., 1968. (Folder 29: 15)
  - "Militarische Loesung des Vietnam-Problems? Chinas Sieg in den Vereinten Nationen," (Military solution to the Viet Nam probelm? China's victory in the UN), Typescript (carbon copy). (Folder 29: 16)
  - "Minimum-Anerkennung fuer Maximum-Leiden," (Minimum recognition for maximum suffering), Aufbau, Printed copy., August 17, 1962. (Folder 29: 17)
  - "Ein Minister a.D., ein Senator, ein Wissen-schaftler--USA Probleme in ihrer Beurteilung," (A cabinet secretary, a senator, a scientist, America's problems in their judgment), Jedioth Chadashoth, Typescript and printed copy., October 19, 1969. (Folder 29: 18)
  - Notes and printed fragments. (Folder 29: 19-20)
  - Typescripts. (Folder 29: 21-22)
  - Letters to the editor. Printed copy. (Folder 29: 23)
  - Printed matter. (Folder 29: 24)
  - "Der missbrauchte Konrad Adenauer," (The abused K.A.), Typescript (carbon copy)., 1968. (Folder 29: 25)
  - "Mit der Rechten ist es immer va banque," (With the right things are always va banque), Jedioth Chadashoth, Typescript and printed copy., September 16, 1969. (Folder 29: 26)
  - "Mit kalkuliertem Risiko, die permanente Vietnam Diskussion in den Vereinigten Staaten," (With calculated risk, the permanent Viet Nam discussion in the US), Vorwaerts, Printed copy., September 4, 1969. (Folder 29: 27)
  - "Mit Milliarden-Defizit in den Weltraum," (With a deficit of billions, into space,) Jedioth Chadashoth, Printed copy., August 18, 1971. (Folder 29: 28)
  - "Mit Riesenschritten dem Buergerkrieg entgegen, die wachsenden Student enunruhen in ganz Amerika," (With giant steps toward civil war, the growing student unrest in all America), Jedioth Chadashoth, Printed copy., May 9, 1969. (Folder 29: 29)
  - "Mit schweren Herzen," (With a heavy heart), Typescript (carbon copy)., n.d. (Folder 29: 30)
  - "Monumentale Aufgaben, ungenuegende Loesungsversuche," (Monumental tasks, insufficient efforts at solutions), Boletin informativo, Printed copy., June 1968. (Folder 29: 31)
  - "Die moralische Krise in den USA," Tagwacht, Typescript and printed copies., December 8, 1969. (Folder 29: 32)
  - "Die moralische und politische Krise in den Vereinigten Staaten," (the moral and political crisis in the US), Typescript (carbon copy). (Folder 29: 33)
  - "Der moralischer Puls schlaegt schwaecher," (The moral pulse is weaker), Telegraf, Reprints., n.d. (Folder 29: 34)
  - "Moralischer Wandel in den USA," (Moral change in the US), Tagwacht, Printed copy., June 23, 1969. (Folder 29: 35)
  - "Moratorium fuer Nixon? Das Vietnam Debakel," Typescript (carbon copy). (Folder 29: 36)
  - "Der Mord an Martin Luther King, eine americanische Tragoedie," Boletin informativo, Printed copy., May 1968. (Folder 29: 37)
  - "Moerder aus Angst! Zu dem Freispruch des SS Obersturmfuehrers Lucas," (Murderer from fear! On the release of SS leader Lucas), Aufbau, Printed copy., December 25, 1970. (Folder 29: 38)
  - "Ein Moerder ist ein Moerder, nach der Ermordung Martin Luther Kings ein seltsamer Prozess in Memphis," (A murderer is a murderer, after the murder of M.L.K., a strange trial in M.), Vorwaerts, Printed copy., March 29, 1969. (Folder 29: 39)
  - "Der Moskau-Vertrag und die USA," (The Moscow treaty and the US), Tagwacht, Printed copy., August 13, 1970. (Folder 29: 40)
  - "Mr. Joint ist tot," Aufbau, Printed copy., June 25, 1965. (Folder 29: 41)
  - "Mr. Melvin Laird: die Debatte um das ABM System spitzt sich zu," (M.L.: the debate about the ABM system is getting sharper), Vorwaerts, Printed copy., July 3, 1969. (Folder 29: 42)
  - "Muss General Westmoreland angeklagt werden? Nuernberg und Vietnam: Eine amerikanische Tragoedie," (Should W. be tried?), Typescript (carbon copy). (Folder 29: 43)
  - "My Lai und das Gewissen der USA," (M.L. and the conscience of the US), Tagwacht, Printed copy., April 3, 1971. (Folder 29: 44)
  - "Die mysterioese Geschichte des Begnadigten Fred W. Edel," (The mysterious story of the pardoned F.W.E.), Deutsche Presse Agentur, Mimeographed copy., January 1957. (Folder 29: 45)
  - "NPD und Wiedergutmachung," (The National Party of Germany and restitution), Typescript (carbon copy)., 1969. (Folder 29: 46)
  - "Nach den Moratorium, Demonstrationen," Tagwacht, Printed copy., November 27, 1969. (Folder 29: 47)
  - "Nach 30 Jahren die Tschechoslowakei wieder besucht," Typescript (carbon copies). (Folder 29: 48)
  - "Nach fuenfundzwanzig Jahren...Die Geschichte als Lehrmeister," (After 25 years, history as teacher), Mimeographed copies., 1963. (Folder 29: 49)
  - "Nach Nixons Rueckkehr," (After N.'s return), Tagwacht, Printed copy., March 11, 1969. (Folder 29: 50)
  - "Nach Nixons Vietnam-Rede," (After Nixon's Viet Nam speech), Tagwacht, April 27, 1970. (Folder 29: 51)
  - "Nach zwanzig Jahren, Gedanken anlaeslich der Wiederkehr des 9. November," (After 20 years, thoughts on the anniversary of the 9th of November), Mimeographed copy., 1958. (Folder 29: 52)
  - "Nachkriegswanderungs probleme," (Post war immigration problems), Typescript (carbon copy) and related material. (Folder 29: 53)
  - "Die Nacht des Vergessens lauert," (The night of forgetting waits), Telegraf, Reprints., n.d. (Folder 29: 54)
  - "Nachwort zum Chicago-Prozess," (Postscript to the Chicago trial), Tagwacht, Printed copy., March 4, 1970. (Folder 29: 55)
  - "Nahostkrieg, ein Jahr spaeter," (Near East War one year later), Aufbau, Printed copy., June 21, 1968. (Folder 29: 56)
  - "Nahum Goldmann und der Zionismus," Rheinischer Merkur, Printed copy., January 8, 1971. (Folder 29: 57)
  - "Nationalistic and Reactionary Germany Might Try it a Third Time," S.A. Jewish Times, Printed copy., November 12, 1948. (Folder 30: 1)
  - "Naziopfer aus Oesterreich, Stiefkinder der Wiedergutmachung," (Nazi victims from Austria, stepchildren of restitution), Neue Welt, Reprints., January 1967. (Folder 30: 2)
  - "The Nazis and the Right of Asylum," Typescript (carbon copy). (Folder 30: 3)
  - "Die Negerfrage und die Kennedy-Regierung," (The black question and the Kennedy administration), Typescript (carbon copy). (Folder 30: 4)
  - "The Neo-Nazis," Jewish Frontier, Printed copy., June 1951. (Folder 30: 5)
  - "Der neue deutsche Boschafter in Israel," (The new German ambassador to Israel), Boletin informativo, Printed copy., May 1971. (Folder 30: 6)
  - "Der neue Deutsche Bundestag und die Wieder-gutmachung," (The new German parliament and restitution), Aufbau, Printed copy., November 5, 1965. (Folder 30: 7)
  - "Eine neue Nahostpolitik?" (A new Near East policy?), Tagwacht, Printed copy., December 4, 1968. (Folder 30: 8)
  - "Der neue Nixon ist ein Maerchen, Agnew ist fuer Humphrey ein Geschenk des Himmels," (The new N. is a fairy tale, Agnew is a gift from heaven for H.), Vorwaerts, Printed copy., August 22, 1968. (Folder 30: 9)
  - "Ein neuer Tag im USA-Sueden," (A new day in the American South), Tagwacht, Typescript and printed copy., July 30, 1971. (Folder 30: 10)
  - "1968 ein aussenpolitischer Rueckblick," (1968, looking back on foreign policy), Tagwacht, Printed copy., December 26, 1968. (Folder 30: 11)
  - "Der 1970 Wahlkampf hat schon begonnen," (The 1970 election campaign has already begun), Typescript (carbon copy)., n.d. (Folder 30: 12)
  - "1972: Chance fuer Demokraten?" (1972: Chance for the Democrats?), Tagwacht, Printed copy., July 24, 1970. (Folder 30: 13)
  - "New Yorker Ausscheidungswahlen mit einigen Ueberraschungen," (N.Y. primaries with some surprises), Jedioth Chadashoth, Typescript and printed copies., July 7, 1970. (Folder 30: 14)
  - "New Yorker Debatte um Hochhuths Stellvertreter." (N.Y. debate over H's The Deputy), Typescript (carbon copy)., n.d. (Folder 30: 15)
  - "Die New Yorker Polizei streikt," Typescript (carbon copy)., n.d. (Folder 30: 16)
  - "New Yorks soziale Einrichtungen: Bienenhaus 1674 Broadway,' (New Yorks social facilities: Beehive on 1674 B.), Aufbau, Reprints., August 3, 1951. (Folder 30: 17)
  - "Newark hat anders entschieden," (Newark decided differently), Tagwacht, Printed copy., June 26, 1970. (Folder 30: 18)
  - "Nicht das wieviel-sondern das wasfuer?" (Not the how much but what for?), Aufbau, Printed copy., September 30, 1960. (Folder 30: 19)
  - "Nicht geeinte Nationen," (Disunited nations), Tagwacht, Printed copy., October 18, 1971. (Folder 30: 20)
  - "Nicht Hass, aber gesunder Menschenverstand," (Not hate but healthy human reason), Typescript (carbon copy). (Folder 30: 21)
  - "Nicht Wohlwollen, unser Recht! Es geht um das Wiedergutmachungsprinzip," (Not patronage, but our right! It is a matter of restitution principle), Aufbau, Printed copy., March 6, 1964. (Folder 30: 22)
  - "Die Niederlage der USA in der UNO," (The defeat of the US in the UN), Tagwacht, Typescript and printed copy., November 1, 1971. (Folder 30: 23)
  - "Nixon auf der politischen Talbahn?" (N. on the political downward path?) Jedioth Chadashoth, Printed copies., July 10, 1970. (Folder 30: 24)
  - "Nixon auf Zick-Zack Kurs," (N. on a zig zag path), Tagwacht, Printed copy., February 9, 1970. (Folder 30: 25)
  - "Nixon bezahlt seine Schulden," (N. pays his debts), Tagwacht, Printed copy., June 7, 1969. (Folder 30: 26)
  - "Nixon braucht die Demokraten,' (N. needs the Democrats), Vorwaerts, Printed copy., November 14, 1968. (Folder 30: 27)
  - "Nixon fest im Sattel?" (N. firm in the saddle?), Tagwacht, Typescript and printed copy., August 18, 1969. (Folder 30: 28)
  - "Nixon fuehrt im Gallup-Poll," (N. leads in the Gallup Poll), Jedioth Chadashoth, Printed copy., December 27, 1971. (Folder 30: 29)
  - "Nixon im Kreuzfeuer der Kritik," (N. in the crossfire of criticism), Jedioth Chadashoth, Printed copy., June 30, 1970. (Folder 30: 30)
  - "Nixon in der Offensive," Tagwacht, Printed copy., September 26, 1970. (Folder 30: 31)
  - "Nixon ist derjenige... " (N. is the one), Typescript (carbon copy)., n.d. (Folder 30: 32)
  - "Nixon kehrt heim," (N. returns home), Typescript (carbon copy)., n.d. (Folder 30: 33)
  - "Nixon nach zwei Jahren," (N. after two years), Boletin informativo, Typescript and printed copies., March 1971. (Folder 30: 34)
  - "Die Nixon Strategie fuer 1972," Tagwacht, Typescript and printed copies., May 22, 1971. (Folder 30: 35)
  - "Nixon sucht neue Gesichter," (N. is looking for new faces), Tagwacht, Printed copy., December 7, 1968. (Folder 30: 36)
  - "Nixon und das amerikanische Dilemma," Tagwacht, Typescript and printed copy., November 11, 1969. (Folder 30: 37)
  - "Nixon und der Kongress," Tagwacht, Typescript and printed copy., August 21, 1970. (Folder 30: 38)
  - "Nixon und die Neger," (N. and blacks), Tagwacht, Typescript and printed copy., July 12, 1969. (Folder 30: 39)
  - "Nixon und die Presse," Typescript (carbon copy). (Folder 30: 40)
  - "Nixon und die UN," Vorwaerts, Printed copy., January 9, 1964. (Folder 30: 41)
  - "Nixon wirbt um die Sympathie des Volkes," (N. seeks the sympathy of the people), Jedioth Chadashoth, Typescript and printed copy., April 23, 1971. (Folder 30: 42)
  - "Nixon zoegert, Spannung waechst," (N. hesitates, tension grows), Tagwacht, Printed copy., April 22, 1969. (Folder 30: 43)
  - "Nixons Amerika," Vorwaerts, Printed copy., January 1, 1970. (Folder 30: 44)
  - "Nixons Dilemma," Jedioth Chadashoth, Typescript and printed copy., September 2, 1971. (Folder 30: 45)
  - "Nixons Europereise," (N.'s trip to Europe), Tagwacht, Printed copy., February 21, 1969. (Folder 30: 46)
  - "Nixons Flitterwochen sind vorueber," (N.'s honeymoon is over), Tagwacht, Printed copy., March 15, 1969. (Folder 30: 47)
  - "Nixons historische Reise nach China," Typescript (carbon copy)., n.d. (Folder 30: 48)
  - "Nixons Kabinett," Vorwaerts, Printed copy., December 19, 1968. (Folder 30: 49)
  - "Nixons Krieg," (N.'s war), Typescript (carbon copy)., n.d. (Folder 30: 50)
  - "Nixons Operation Sieg," (N.'s operation victory), Jedioth Chadashoth, Printed copy., May 17, 1970. (Folder 30: 51)
  - "Nixons Reise im Schatten des Monderfolges," (N.'s trip in the shadow of the successful moon shot), Tagwacht, Typescript and printed copy., July 29, 1969. (Folder 30: 52)
  - "Nixons Vietnam-Initiative," Vorwaerts, Printed copy., May 2, 1969. (Folder 30: 53)
  - "Noch Chance, LBJ?" Vorwaerts, Printed copy., November 30, 1967. (Folder 30: 54)
  - "Eine notwendige Wiedergutmachungsbilanz," (A necessary assessment of restitution), Die Mahnung, Typescript and printed copies., March 1, 1970. (Folder 30: 55)
  - "Nur ein Tag in den USA," (Just a day in the US), Tagwacht, Printed copy., April 6, 1970. (Folder 30: 56)
  - "Nuernberg und die 1949iger Rote Kreuz Konvention," (Nuernberg and the 1949 Red Cross convention), Typescript (carbon copy). (Folder 30: 57)
  - "Nuernberg und Vietnam, amerikanische Tragoedie." Jedioth Chadashoth, Printed copy., January 24, 1971. (Folder 30: 58)
  - "Oberstes Bundesgericht im Geist Nixons," (The Supreme Court in the spirit of Nixon), Tagwacht, Typescript and printed copy., October 28, 1971. (Folder 30: 59)
  - "Die offene, nicht so offene Gesellschaft in USA," (The open, not so open society in the US), Typescript (carbon copy)., November 16, 1971. (Folder 30: 60)
  - "Eine offizioese Stimme zum Schlussgesetz," (An official vote on the final law), Aufbau, Printed copy., February 22, 1963. (Folder 30: 61)
  - "Ohne dritten Weltkrieg," (Without a third world war), Tagwacht, Printed copy., September 28, 1971. (Folder 30: 62)
  - "ORT hilft den unentwickelten Laendern," (ORT aids underdeveloped countries), Aufbau, Printed copy., July 14, 1961. (Folder 30: 63)
  - "Oscar Schindlers dankbare Kinder," (O. S.'s thankful children), Jedioth Chadashoth, Printed copy., January 28, 1972. (Folder 30: 64)
  - Ossietzky eulogy, Typescript and related material., 1938. (Folder 30: 65)
  - Ossietzky: Ein deutscher Patriot, final form published in Munich, Kindler Verlag, Outline. Typescript., 1963. (Folder 30: 66)
    - Prospectus. Typescript, mimeographed and printed copies. (Folder 30: 67)
    - Reviews. Typescript, mimeographed and printed copies. (Folder 30: 68)
    - Speech, given in acceptance of the Albert Schweitzer book prize for Ossietzky, Mimeographed copy., January 13, 1963. (Folder 30: 69)
  - "Ossietzky, Soukoup, Masary," Aufbau, Reprint., December 6, 1946. (Folder 31: 1)
  - "Ostdeutschland gegen Wiedergutmachung," (East Germany vs. restitution), Aufbau, Typescript and printed copy., January 2, 1953. (Folder 31: 2)
  - "Oesterreich--Vertreibungsbegiet?" (Austria--refugee area?), Aufbau, Printed copies., October 7, 1966. (Folder 31: 3)
  - "Das oesterreichische Wiedergutmachungs-dilemma," (The Austrian restitution dilemma), Neue Welt, Printed copy., June 1968. (Folder 31: 4)
  - "Oesterreichs Zwischenzeitgesetz," (Austria's intermediate law), Aufbau, Printed copies., November 14, 1969. (Folder 31: 5)
  - "Otto Strasser," Typescript., c. 1940. (Folder 31: 6)
  - "Parteitag der Spaltung," (Party convention of division), Tagwacht, Printed copy., September 3, 1968. (Folder 31: 7)
  - "Peace and the German Problem," New Europe, Photocopy., February 1943. (Folder 31: 8)
  - "Pentagon-Gefangener," (Captive of the Pentagon), Vorwaerts, Printed copy., June 12, 1969. (Folder 31: 9)
  - "Das Pentagon regiert die Stunde, findet Praesident Johnson doch noch einen Ausweg?" (The Pentagon rules, will J. find a way out?), Vorwaerts, Printed copy., September 28, 1967. (Folder 31: 10)
  - "Die Philadelphia Formel," (The Philadelphia formula), Jedioth Chadashoth, Typescript and printed copy., October 22, 1969. (Folder 31: 11)
  - "Piratenkrieg in der Luft," (Pirate war in the air), Tagwacht, Printed copy., February 22, 1969. (Folder 31: 12)
  - "The Plot Against DP Immigration," American Jewish Congress news release, Mimeographed copies., January 20, 1950. (Folder 31: 13)
  - "Plumpe Propagandagruesse aus Ostdeutschland," (Clumsy propaganda greetings from East Germany), Aufbau, Typescript and printed copy., December 28, 1951. (Folder 31: 14)
  - "Poison in Germany's Bloodstream," Congress Bi-Weekly, Mimeographed copy., 1964. (Folder 31: 15)
  - "Polish-German Understandign from the Past to the Present," Typescript. (Folder 31: 16)
  - "Politikum," Vorawerts, Printed copy., January 16, 1969. (Folder 31: 17)
  - "Portorikaner in New York," (Puerto Ricans in N.Y.) Typescript (carbon copy). (Folder 31: 18)
  - "Der Praesident im Elfenbeinturm," (The President in an ivory tower), Tagwacht, Typescript and printed copy., June 15, 1970. (Folder 31: 19)
  - "Praesident Nixon und die Rebellen," (President N. and the rebels), Jedioth Chadashoth, Printed copy., April 25, 1969. (Folder 31: 20)
  - "Der Praedident und der Leutnant," (The president and the lieutenant), Typescript (carbon copy). (Folder 31: 21)
  - "Der Praesident wurde deutlich," (The President was clear), Vorwaerts, Printed copy., January 9, 1967. (Folder 31: 22)
  - "Prioritaet der Ansprueche Israels anerkannt," (Priorities of Israels demands recognized), Allgemeine, Duesseldorf, Printed copies., November 2, 1951. (Folder 31: 23)
  - "Die Prioritaet der moralischen Werte," (The priority of moral values), Freiheit und Recht, Printed copy., October 1971. (Folder 31: 24)
  - "Problem Georgia," Vorwaerts, Printed copy., December 7, 1966. (Folder 31: 25)
  - "The Problem of Forgetting, the Trials and the Statute of Limitations," Typescript., November 26, 1968. (Folder 31: 26)
  - "Die Problematik der KZ-Liste," (The problem of the camp list), Jedioth Chadashoth, Printed copy., October 31, 1969. (Folder 31: 27)
  - "Probleme der Alten von drueben," (Problems of the elderly from over there), Typescript., c. 1961. (Folder 31: 28)
  - "Probleme und Implikationen nach dem Moratorium Demonstrationen," Typescript (carbon copy). (Folder 31: 29)
  - "The Promise of Indemnification: It May Take 15 Years," The ADL Bulletin, Printed copy., April 1956. (Folder 31: 30)
  - "The Propaganda in the Battle for Democracy," Typescript (carbon copy). (Folder 31: 31)
  - "Die Propagandaschlacht in den USA ist noch nicht gewonnen," (The Propaganda battle in the US is not yet won), Jedioth Chadashoth, Printed copy., April 2, 1969. (Folder 31: 32)
  - "Protection for Civilians in Time of War," Typescript (carbon copy)., n.d. (Folder 31: 33)
  - "The Protection of Civilian Persons in Time of War," Mimeographed copies., c. 1950. (Folder 31: 34)
  - "Die Protestbewegung lebt weiter," (The protest movement lives on), Tagwacht, Printed copy., May 10, 1971. (Folder 31: 35)
  - "Proteste und Generale," Vorwaerts, Printed copy., May 4, 1967. (Folder 31: 36)
  - "Die Prozess-Farce von Chicago," (The trial farce of Chicago), Tagwacht, Printed copy., February 23, 1970. (Folder 31: 37)
  - "Rache fuer Bob? Sirhan Sirhan erwartet ein Todesurteil," (Revenge for B.? S.S. waits for the death penalty), Vorwaerts, Printed copy., May 8, 1969. (Folder 31: 38)
  - "Randbemerkung zum Wiedergutmachungswerk," (Marginal note on restitution work), Aufbau, Printed copy., August 27, 1965. (Folder 31: 39)
  - "Ratifiziert! Das deutsch-israelische Abkommen vom Bundestag in Bonn angenommen," (Ratified! The German-Israeli agreement is accepted by the parliament in Bonn), Aufbau, Printed copy., March 27, 1953. (Folder 31: 40)
  - "Realistische Ernuechterung," (Realistic sober thoughts), Jedioth Chadashoth, Printed copy., December 31, 1971. (Folder 31: 41)
  - "Das Recht, das mit uns geboren. Irrungen und Verwirrung um das Wiedergutmachun gsprinzip," (The right born with us. Errors and confusion about the restitution principle), Die Mahnung, Printed copy., May 15, 1964. (Folder 31: 42)
  - "Rechtsversorgung und Widersprueche," (Obtaining justice and contradictions) Aufbau, Printed copy., February 25, 1966. (Folder 31: 43)
  - "Reduzierung des Wahlalters," (Lowering the voting age), Tagwacht, Printed copy., June 30, 1970. (Folder 31: 44)
  - "Refugees: Burden or Asset?" The Nation, Typescript and printed copy (photocopy)., December 24, 1942. (Folder 31: 45)
  - "Refugees in Peril," The New York Post, Printed copy., November 20, 1939. (Folder 31: 46)
  - "Refugees to and from Czechoslovakia," Typescript (carbon copy). (Folder 31: 47)
  - "Regierungsdirektor Zorn zum Bundesentschaedigungs-Schlussgesetz," (Government director Z. on the final German restitution law), Aufbau, Printed copy., October 29, 1965. (Folder 31: 48)
  - "Reichsdeutscher oder Oesterreicher? Die Problematik der Rechtsungleichheit," (Citizen of the Third Reich or Austrian? The problem of unequal legal treatment), Aufbau, Typescript and printed copies., November 24, 1967. (Folder 31: 49)
  - "Das reichste Land der Welt kann nicht alle seine Einwohner ernaehern," (The richest country in the world cannot feed all of its inhabitants), Jedioth Chadashoth, Printed copy., December 20, 1970. (Folder 31: 50)
  - "Reisebericht," (Trip report), Typescript (carbon copy)., August 26, 1939. (Folder 31: 51)
  - "Remarque und die Wirklichkeit," (R. and reality), Typescript (carbon copy). (Folder 31: 52)
  - "Rentenerhoehungen und die vier Kategorien," (Pension increases and the four catagories), Aufbau, Printed copy., June 24, 1966. (Folder 31: 53)
  - "Rententabellen und Bundesfinanzministerium," (Pension tables and the German Finance Ministry), Aufbau, Printed copy., April 8, 1966. (Folder 31: 54)
  - "Die Rententabellen werden revidiert," (The pension tables are being revised), Aufbau, Printed copy., July 31, 1970. (Folder 31: 55)